And welcome to week two, day two, as we continue our adventure into the realm of LMS.
둘째 주, 둘째 날입니다 LMS 왕국으로의 모험은 계속되죠
Uh, so today, a very special day that I'm really looking forward to.
오늘은 제가 정말 기대하고 있는 아주 특별한 날이에요
Uh, quick recap.
요약해 보죠
Of course, you can now describe Transformers as well, and you can talk about six top frontier models.
이제는 트랜스포머도 묘사할 수 있어요 최고의 개척자 모델 6명도 말할 수 있죠
You can confidently use OpenAI's API along with Anthropic and Google's.
오픈AI의 API 또한 앤스로픽, 구글과 함께 사용할 수 있죠
But today, changing topic, we are going to be talking about Gradio.
오늘은 주제를 바꿔서 그라디오에 관해 얘기해 볼게요
And I realized I have gone on about Gradio a bit, but you're going to see why.
비트에 대해 너무 많이 얘기했네요 이유를 알게 될 거예요
It's really terrific and we're going to have fun with it.
정말 멋진 작품이고 재미있게 만들 거예요
We're going to create a simple UI using radio and then hook it up to Frontier Models.
라디오를 이용해 간단한 UI를 만들고 프론티어 모델에 연결할 거예요
And as I say, it's going to be easy.
말씀드렸듯이 쉬울 거예요
Uh, so why make such a fuss about user interfaces?
그런데 왜 사용자 인터페이스를 두고 그렇게 소란을 피우는 거죠?
Because it allows us, as data scientists, as LM engineers, to do more quickly, to be able to build
데이터 과학자나 LMS 엔지니어로서 시제품을 더 빨리 만들
prototypes, expose them to our audience, to our business sponsors, the the, the people that need
수 있고 고객과 비즈니스 스폰서 LMS가 필요한 사람들에게 빠르게
our LMS and do so very quickly indeed.
노출할 수 있으니까요
If you are a front end person or you've dabbled in front end and you know what it's like to stand up
여러분이 프런트엔드를 사용하거나 약간 해본 적이 있다면 리액트 앱 같은 것을
a react app or something like that, you know that there's a lot of boilerplate code that goes into
세우는 것이 어떤 것인지 알 수 있습니다 무언가를 올리고 실행하는 데에는 많은 상용
getting things up and running, and it turns out that we don't need to do that with models.
코드가 있습니다 모델과 함께 할 필요가 없다는 것이 밝혀졌죠
We can build a user interface super quickly, and that's what we'll be doing today.
사용자 인터페이스를 아주 빨리 만들 수 있어요 그게 오늘 할 일이죠
So Gradio is in fact, uh, a part of Hugging Face.
그러니까 그라디오는 페이스 포옹의 일부예요
It was a startup that was acquired by Hugging Face a couple of years ago.
몇 년 전 페이스 포옹으로 인수한 스타트업 회사예요
So Gradio is part of the Hugging Face family.
그래디오는 포옹하는 얼굴 가족이에요
Uh, and as it says on the landing page there, it lets you build and share delightful machine learning
랜딩 페이지에 적혀 있듯이 즐거운 머신 러닝 앱을 만들고 공유할 수 있어요
apps.
당신도 좋아할 거예요
Uh, so I promised you it was easy.
쉬울 거라고 약속했죠
It really is easy, as you will see.
보시면 알겠지만 정말 쉬워요
What it comes down to is there is this magical line import Gradio as GR, which is the way people do
결국 그라디오를 GR로 불러오는 마술적인 경계가 있어요 사람들이 그렇게
it.
하죠
You write a function, any function, a function to do a task.
어떤 함수든 작업을 위한 함수를 작성하세요
In this case, the function that they've written here is greet takes a name and it replies hello name.
이 경우 Greet라는 함수가 있는데 이름을 취하면 hello name을 응답하죠
And then you can create a user interface based on that function, give it inputs and outputs, and you're
함수를 기반으로 사용자 인터페이스를 생성하고 입력과 출력을 제공하면
going to get a user interface built for you just like that.
사용자 인터페이스가 만들어지는 거예요
And that is what we're going to do.
그게 우리가 할 일이죠
So what we're going to do now is create a UI for API calls to GPT and Claude and Gemini, so that you
이제 GPT와 클로드와 제미니에 API 호출을 위한 UI를 생성하겠습니다 이걸 어떻게 노출하는지
can see how to expose this.
보실 수 있게요
We are then going to go ahead and create a UI for the brochure that we built in the last week's lectures.
그런 다음 지난 강의에서 만든 브로슈어의 UI를 생성할 거예요
And so that's going to allow us to really package up our application into a nice business app with prototype
그래서 응용 프로그램을 프로토타입 스크린이 있는 멋진 비즈니스 앱으로 패키지할 수 있게
screens.
해주죠
And of course, we'll throw into the mix streaming and markdown into a UI, since we're pretty good
물론 믹스 스트리밍과 마크다운을 UI에 넣을 거예요 이미 꽤 잘
with that already, that's going to be the plan.
하고 있으니까요 그게 계획이 될 거예요
Let's go over to the lab and get on with it.
Get it, get it, get it, it! 실험실로 가서 검사해 보죠